

**SUMMARY** 

Full Stack Developer (Java) with 6 Years' experience in Angular JS, Spring Boot, Spring microservices, Hibernate, JPA, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Java/J2EE, Rabbit MQ, Kendo UI, Jenkins and Maven.

Successful background in development of Real Time Trade Monitoring platform for Equity/Forex, loan cycle platform, and multiple 3-tier based applications.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## 2015 - Present ASSISTANT MANAGER

Edelweiss Financial Services, Mumbai.

Drive the design, development and testing of multiple Fintech (Financial Technology) applications. Delivered applications for trade monitoring, loan management and secure data sharing across organization.

### 2014 – 2015 **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Pratham Software Pvt. Ltd., Jaipur.

Responsible for designing, development and testing of significant components in BPM application, created workflows for credit document data capture and developed a web application for publishing workflow data.

## **2013 – 2014 JAVA DEVELOPER**

Midnight Oxygen Pvt. Ltd., Jaipur.

Developed an attendance management system along with multiple three tier web-based applications.

# **EDUCATION**

2010 – 2013 MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATIONS Suresh Gyan Vihar University, *Jaipur*.

GPA - 8.38/10

2007 – 2010 BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATIONS

University of Rajasthan, Jaipur.

GPA - 67/100

8A- WINNIE HOUSE, KALINA MARKET,

MUMBAI- 400098

+91 (989) 298 6762

MOHITARORA.J2EE@GMAIL.COM

#### CONNECT

mohitarora.herokuapp.com linkedin.com/in/mohitaroralive github.com/imohitarora facebook.com/live.mohitarora twitter.com/i m mohit

#### **AWARDS**

WALKING THE EXTRA MILE – 2018 EMERGING LEADER 2018 – 19

### **SKILLS**

#### PROGRAMMING/

#### **FRAMEWORK**

JAVA/J2EE

ANGULARJS/ANGULAR

NodeJS

**SPRINGBOOT** 

SPRING FRAMEWORK

JPA

**HIBERNATE** 

**JHIPSTER** 

MICROSERVICES

JUNIT

HTML5

**CSS** 

**JQUERY** 

KENDOUI

**HIGH CHARTS** 

WEBIX FILEMANAGER

**WEBSOCKET** 

### DATABASE/TOOLS/OS

**POSTGRESQL** 

Mongodb

MSSQL SERVER

**ECLIPSE** 

MAVEN

**JENKINS** 

JIRA

BITBUCKET/GIT/SVN

# **PROJECTS**

# QUBER - (LOAN MANAGEMENT SYSTEM) [Edelweiss Group, MUMBAI, IN]

Duration: Jan 2017 – Present [Parallel LIVE]

Team Size: 15

- Role: Full Stack Developer & Team Lead

- **Skills Used:** Java 8, Spring boot/Security, PostgreSQL, Kendo UI, Angular JS

This system manages a complete loan lifecycle for business. Reserve bank of India (RBI) has mandate for each Non-Banking Financial Company-Micro Finance Institutions (NBFC-MFIs) to have system for loans. Using this system, a user can manage sanction, collateral, disbursement, repayment, accounting, NPA and loan closure. Reports are generated from the system and sent to RBI.

# SHARESPACE – [Edelweiss Group, MUMBAI, IN]

- **Duration:** Oct 2016 – Dec 2016

- Team Size: 1

- Role: Designer, Developer and Tester

- Skills Used: Java 8, Spring boot/Security, PostgreSQL, Kendo UI, Angular JS, SECLORE

Application is created with an integration with SECLORE (Data-Centric Security System) to share documents outside of organization with clients and auditors. System works as a file management system, every file shared via system is encrypted and accessible only by permissions provided in the system such as view, read or write. Admin penal is there to allocate permissions in the system.

## ORION – (RISK MANAGEMENT SYSTEM) [Edelweiss Group, MUMBAI, IN]

Duration: July 2015 – Oct 2016

- Team Size: 3

Role: Designer, Developer and Tester

- Skills Used: Java 8, Java FX, Spring, MongoDB, Rabbit MQ

Orion is a trade monitoring application, which provides real time data of the trades that are executed on Stock Exchange in Edelweiss, System calculates span, delta and other critical risk parameters for dealers and traders. Traders can create basket orders (directional/arbitrage/roll/machine gun) in the system and execute on trading platform.

# SAVVION - (BPM) [Pratham Software Pvt. Ltd., JAIPUR, IN]

Duration: July 2014 – July 2015

Team Size: 3

Role: Developer and Tester

Skills Used: Java, Spring, Savvion BPM, Oracle

A web application laying under the architecture of and integrated with Savvion BPM. Application users processed customer documents and stored data in another application following the workflow defined in BPM.

# **REFERENCES**

References available on request